MELISA LARSON

(805) 291-9658 | larsonmelisa@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/melisalarson | github.com/melisalarson

Full Stack Software Engineer

I am a full-stack software engineer with a background in client-facing B2B roles. I have experience working on projects cross-departmentally and implementing new software systems within my organization. I want to help build software that minimizes and automates administrative work to get people back to the work they love. With over 6 years of fast-paced start-up experience I am able to take on multiple responsibilities, while meeting and exceeding goals.

SKILLS

Software Proficiencies

WageWorks, Fidelity, Microsoft Office Suite, Salesforce, Zenefits, Confluence, Jira, Slack, Okta, Google Apps, Windows, iOS

Payroll Proficiencies

ADP, Paychex, Gusto, Intuit, Quickbooks, Zenefits Payroll, Namely

Coding Proficiencies

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Mongo, Mongoose, Node, Express, ejs, Bootstrap, Python, Django, Postres, Materialize, React

PROJECTS

appTrac - Full stack web Application built using a MERN stack

the Spot - Full stack web Application built using Python, Django, Postgres, and Materialize

Chisme - Collaboration focused/driven 24 hour project with UX/UI designers to build a landing page

easyDo - Full stack web Application built using Javascript, Node, Express, Mongo, Mongoose, and Bootstrap

Tamagotchi - Single page application built using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

General Assembly San Francisco, CA

JUN 2020 - AUG 2020

As a student of the Software Engineering Immersive class at General Assembly I learned many coding languages and developed 5 applications. I also collaborated with engineers and UX/UI designers.

SABBATICAL TRAVEL

South America SEP 2019 - MAR 2020

To experience different cultures, lifestyles, and traditions, I traveled to various countries and cities within South America. An unforgettable and tremendously rewarding opportunity.

PAYROLL MANAGER

Demandbase San Francisco, CA

NOV 2017 - SEP 2019

As a member of the Finance team at Demandbase, I was the one responsible for processing payroll twice a month, assisting employees with their payroll needs, analyzing current processes and implementing more efficient ones, and auditing benefits and deductions.

- Prepared and processed semi-monthly full cycle U.S. multi state, exempt and non-exempt payroll for 300+ employees (ADP Workforce)
- Audited and processed monthly commission and quarterly bonus payouts, as well as, tracked, calculated, and processed SDR compensation
- Managed the implementation of ADP Workforce and the transition away from Paylocity.

Projects: Created payroll master file - Processed 401k and Workers Comp audits - Restructured SDR compensation plan

PAYROLL SPECIALIST

Upwork San Francisco, CA

JUN 2016 - NOV 2017

As a member of the Finance team at Upwork, I was responsible for preparing payroll twice a month, partnering with HR for new hire onboarding, and implementing more efficient workflows.

- Prepared semi-monthly full cycle U.S. multi state, exempt and non-exempt payroll for 200+ employees (Namely)
- Partnered with Human Resources on all matters involving employee records
- Registered for state withholding and unemployment insurance

Projects: Conducted third-party quarterly reconciliations - Built and actively presented new hire payroll presentations - Prepared hourly employees' overtime analysis - Lead implementation of hourly schedule adjustment for more accurate payments

CLIENT SUCCESS - PAYROLL SPECIALIST

Zenefits San Francisco, CA

FEB 2017 - JUN 2016

As a member of the Client Success team at Zenefits, I was responsible for investigating and understanding client reported issues, communicating with the engineering team to resolve these issues, and educating clients to self-serve.

- Worked closely with engineers and product teams to: assist in the development of new products and processes; communicate bugs, clients' requests, and product recommendations
- Maintained and managed a large queue of correspondence with clients within required timelines and guidelines to provided prompt, courteous, and efficient customer service
- Establish and manage S-Corp Owner and Imputed Income accounts
- Ensured EE deductions and ER contributions are properly set up and managed in Zenefits and in payroll
- Provided training on payroll related topics to other peers within and outside of my department; including but not limited to new hire training

Projects: Provided payroll training to associates - Imputed income implementation and communication - Demoed new payroll system (PYP) at launch

EDUCATION

General Assembly - Software Engineering Immersive (2020) California State University Northridge - B.S. Business Management (2010)